## **MEGHAN O'CONNOR**

### UI/UX Designer

https://www.behance.net/meghanoconno

### **SUMMARY**

Creative and organized UX designer with an education background and over a decade of experience planning, designing, creating, and implementing various tasks to meet users' needs. Eager to lead meetings, to identify weak points, and present improvements in products.

#### **TOOLS**

Figma Marvel Sketch Visual Studio Code

### **SKILLS**

User Research
Wireframing & Prototyping
Usability Testing
UX Design
UI Design
Accessibility Assessment
Team Leadership
User Persona
User Flow and Journey

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **UX DESIGN**

CAREER FOUNDRY

June 2020-January 2023

## MASTER'S IN SPECIAL EDUCATION

• GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY

June 2016-December 2018

## BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN EDUCATION

• UNIVERSITY OF DELAWARE August 2009-May 2013

### **CONTACT**



moconnor0807@gmail.com



609-647-3961



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ meghan-o-connor-581706252/

### **UX/UI PROJECTS**

#### **CURBAROO • PROPERTY WEB APPLICATION ALLOWING USERS TO SEARCH LOCAL REAL-ESTATE**

- Applied a mobile-first design that included several screen iterations across multiple breakpoints
  resulting in a consistent feeling application (app) that invited users to experience the app across
  various devices.
- Designed a property web app by analyzing user persona and user research, creating user flows, mood boards, and UI elements using Figma, Figmotion, and Marvel. View the project here: CURBAROO

#### SEE SPOT RUN • FITNESS APPLICATION ENABLING USERS TO TRACK FITNESS GOALS

- Developed an interactive prototype that resulted in an increased usability by 50% based on analysis
  using a rainbow spreadsheet and multiple usability tests.
- · Conducted several competitive analyses to identify and capitalize on competitor weak points.
- Integrated a user-first approach through research and the development of user personas, user flows, and user journeys.
- Developed a mobile fitness application by conducting a card sort, developing user personas, completing multiple user interviews, and creating numerous fidelity wireframes with clickable prototypes using Figma, Usability Hub, Optimal Sort, and Sublime. View the project here: SEE SPOT RUN

#### **LUOVA • A STUDY APPLICATION PROVIDING USERS FLASHCARDS TO IMPROVE VOCABULARY**

- Created multiple fidelity wireframes to implement usability tests to provide study tools in one central location.
- Created an on-the-go study application by conducting user research, a competitive analysis, sketching low-fidelity wireframes, and designing mid- and high-fidelity wireframes using Marvel, Figma, and Sketch resulting in a user friendly and high intuitive study tool. View the project here: LUOVA

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## K-2 SPECIAL EDUCATION TEACHER • LOUDOUN COUNTY PUBLIC SCHOOLS, LEESBURG, VA • 2021-PRESENT

- Developed individualized plans to target audience needs, enabling academic, social, and emotional growth.
- Collected, analyzed, presented data, and made data-driven decisions for individual needs resulting
  in plans to move learning and understanding of materials to the next level.
- $\bullet$  Created resources and step by step plans to help students progress toward academic and social gains, resulting in an increase of 92% student achievement.
- Facilitated meetings with colleagues, parents, and students to advocate for individual needs, allowing for a common understanding of information and increased communication between parents and school team members.
- Designed various management techniques that nurtured a collaborative environment, increasing students' intrinsic motivation and productivity.
- Mentored two novice teachers through lesson modeling, peer conferencing, and resource sharing, resulting in 50% retention rate.

## $3^{RD}$ – $5^{TH}$ SPECIAL EDUCATION TEACHER • FAIRFAX COUNTY PUBLIC SCHOOLS, FALLS CHURCH, VA • 2020-2021

- Managed a caseload of students by delivering instruction, differentiating information, and presenting growth to coworkers and parents.
- Created individualized learning plans, with parent buy-in, to meet each student's physical, social, emotional, and educational needs. This resulted in increased participation of students, not only in one-on-one sessions but also in the general education classroom.
- Designed, created, and executed online curriculum and resources for students during distance learning which fostered growth in students' technological skills and continued engagement during the pandemic.
- Collaborated with special education team to develop and implement resources to drive instruction and improve student understanding and retention of academic information.

# 5<sup>TH</sup> GRADE SPECIAL EDUCATION TEACHER • FAIRFAX COUNTY PUBLIC SCHOOLS, FALLS CHURCH, VA • 2019-2020

- Supervised and led meetings focused on data-driven research, creating a collaborative team environment, and increasing student learning.
- Used data to develop customized instruction, increasing students' understanding of information and encouraging an eagerness to participate in future assignments.

Completed Foundational Skills of an Instructional Coaching professional development which focused
on developing leaders and provided a deeper understanding of the human psychology, resulting in
exploring, participating, and implementing aspects of ten coaching roles to enhance adult learning.

#### 3RD GRADE TEACHER • FAIRFAX COUNTY PUBLIC SCHOOLS, FALLS CHURCH, VA • 2015-2019

- Modeled the coaching cycle to over 100 instructional coaches through a county wide professional development which increased an understanding of coaching roles throughout the county.
- Collaborated with team members and facilitated data driven conversations that focused on improving instruction and increasing student understanding.
- Co-planned and implemented reading instruction across 12 groupings that resulted in an increase in reading levels by 73% based on standardized reading assessments.
- Participated and recorded vital information shared during weekly meetings that allowed teachers to improve instruction, assessments, and their analysis of student data.
- Mentored three new teachers and helped build their teaching craft through observations, modeling and monthly reflection meetings which resulted in 100% teacher retention rate.

#### 3RD GRADE TEACHER • ALEXANDRIA PUBLIC SCHOOLS, ALEXANDRIA, VA • 2014 - 2015

- Formulated plans based on data collected and presented materials in an obtainable fashion which increased student engagement and advanced understanding of materials.
- Instructed 48 students of various learning styles and levels, developing robust management techniques and organization skills to increase efficiency and productivity in their general education development.
- Developed detailed plans targeting an increase in mathematics understanding and science vocabulary resulting in 89% pass rate of the state standardized assessment.

#### 2ND GRADE TEACHER • ALEXANDRIA PUBLIC SCHOOLS, ALEXANDRIA, VA • 2014 – 2015

- Created a management system based on research-based evidence that balanced social and emotional needs that resulted in a decrease in administration interventions by 67%.
- Promoted a deeper understanding of the English language to students from various backgrounds using picture prompts and ample visuals resulting in an increase in students verbal vocabulary and reading fluency.